# YUNZHE WANG

784 Columbus Ave, New York, NY

(213) - 421 - 9274 | yw3737@columbia.edu | Home Page: yunzhew.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

With an interdisciplinary passion for Artificial Intelligence and Cognitive Science, I seek to answer: "What is intelligence and how should we recreate it?" I envision General AI emerging in the next 5-10 years, and I want its primary purpose to be assisting and augmenting human capabilities. Keywords below best encapsulates my interests:

Self-supervised Learning, Few-Shot Learning, Multi-Modal Learning, Cognitive Modeling, Intelligent Agent, Multi-Agent System Human-AI Interaction and Collaboration, Augmented Intelligence, Assistive Technologies, AI Safety and Alignment, Fairness

#### **EDUCATION**

**Columbia University** (GPA: 3.96/4.00)

M.S. Computer Science, Machine Learning Track + Advanced Research

Aug 2021 - May 2023

New York, NY

**University of Southern California** (GPA: 3.84/4.00)

B.S. Computational Neuroscience

B.A. Applied Mathematics

Minor Computer Science

Los Angeles, CA Aug 2017 - May 2021

**Relevant Coursework:** Machine Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Applied Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence, Robotics, Cognitive Neuroscience, Sensation and Perception, Neurobiology, Brain Architecture, Cellular and Molecular Neuroscience, Statistics, Probability Theory, Numerical Methods, Calculus, Optimization, Computer Networks, Social Networks, Databases, Data Structure, Algorithm Analysis, Advanced Algorithms

### **EXPERIENCE**

### Bubble Group, Inc. - A leader in the no-code tech domain

Software Engineer II (Artificial Intelligence)

New York, NY Jul 2023 - Present

- Conducted Generative AI research and development in text-to-web-application generation.
- Initiated and led the LLM-Agent Approach, enabling generating stylistic and responsive websites directly from natural language. Emphasized scalability, cost-efficiency, and time.
- Formulated a vision-based Reward Model, conducted LLM-tuning and dataset EDA, and streamlined code integration.

### **Creative Machines Lab at Columbia University**

Student Researcher

New York, NY Sep 2021 - May 2023

Machine Learning and Robotics research with Prof. Hod Lipson

### Project: Conversational Face Robot

- Collaborated on creating a conversational face robot with human-like lip-sync and co-expressive facial dynamics.
- Led the Machine Learning Aspects:
  - o Designed a speech-driven talking face generation model, enhancing the robot with verbal interaction capabilities.
  - o Utilized self-supervised learning, achieving model robustness for varied speakers and languages with limited data.
  - o Utilized GAN, LSTM, and Multi-Modal Transformer architectures, modalities in speech, videos, and 3D landmarks.

### Project: Quadruped Robot Morphology Transfer Learning

- Developed a 12-DOF quadruped robot capable of self-morphology identification and realtime trajectory optimization.
- Led the Machine Learning Aspects:
  - Developed a classifier capable of identifying 12-DOF robot morphologies from motion dynamics, enabled trajectory optimization for robot with unseen morphologies.
  - o Utilized Transfer Learning and Multi-Task Learning; Data modalities in time-series (IMU) and point cloud.

## Cognitive Architecture Lab at USC Institute for Creative Technologies

Feb 2020 - Aug 2021

Los Angeles, CA

Student Researcher

- Reinforcement Learning and Operational Research with Prof. Paul Rosenbloom and Dr. Volkan Ustun.
- Software development for the Graphical Model aspects of the (Py)Sigma Cognitive Architecture.

### Project: DARPA Artificial Social Intelligence for Successful Teams (ASIST)

- Developed a decision-making framework for human search-and-rescue teams, resulting in real-time routing suggestions that surpassed the performance of conventional RL and Linear Programming methods.
- Leveraged Graph Transformer, Reinforcement learning, and Unsupervised Learning; Data modalities in Graph.

# Institute of Computing Technology, Chinese Academy of Science

Beijing, China May 2019 - Aug 2019

Research Internship

- Natural Language Processing Research mentored by Prof. Cungen Cao, focused on Knowledge Extraction.
- Led and developed an expert system to optimize Chinese Part-of-Speech tagging models, leveraging automated datamined rules and advanced pattern matching algorithms.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

# Efficient Transfer Learning Across Robot Morphologies

2022 - 2023

Y. Hu, Y. Wang, R. Liu, Z. Shen, H. Lipson.

Submitted to International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA 2024)

# Lip Synchronization for Animatronic Robot Face

2021 - 2023

Y. Hu, Yu. Wang, B. Chen, Yi. Wang, J. Lin, H. Lipson.

In Submission to Science Robotics

### **Human-Robot Facial Co-expression**

2021 - 2023

Y. Hu, B. Chen, J. Lin, Yu. Wang, Yi. Wang, H. Lipson.

Science Robotics (From Revision)

## Route Optimization in Service of a Search and Rescue Artificial Social Intelligence Agent

2020 - 2021

Y. Wang, N. Gurney, J. Zhou, D. Pynadath, V. Ustun.

Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence 2021 Fall Symposium Series (AAAI FSS 2021)

### **TEACHING**

Applied C	omnuter	Vision	(Teaching	(Assistant)
Applieu C	unputer	V 121011	( i eaciiiii)	, Assistant j

Spring 2023

Introduction to Natural Language Processing (Teaching Assistant)

Fall 2022

Introduction to Natural Language Processing (Teaching Assistant)

Summer 2022

### **AWARDS**

USC Graduate with Distinction (Magna Cum Laude)

Academic Achievement Award, University of Southern California

Dean's List, all semesters, University of Southern California

American Mathematical Contest 12 (top 5%), Mathematical Association of America

### **PROJECTS**

M. D. MAZ., ALTO.	1:1 / 1: 1	2022
Medium Writer on AI Topics	bit.ly/medium-yunzhe	2023
Interactive Visualization of 1.7M Arxiv Papers	bit.ly/arxiv-embed-viz	2023
Audio-Visual Speaker Diarization	bit.ly/syncnet-spk	2023
Unsupervised Neural Machine Translation	bit.ly/unmt-survey	2022
Autonomous Car-Racing Game Agent in Unity	bit.ly/auto-drive-agent	2021

### **SKILLS**

**Programming and Development:** Python, C++, SQL, JavaScript/TypeScript, Git, LaTeX, Web Development, Web Scraping

**AI and Machine Learning:** PyTorch, scikit-learn, Tensor Programming, Data Visualization, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Unsupervised Learning, Sequence Modeling, Prompt Engineering, Large Language Model

Others: Bilingual in English and Chinese, Photography, Drawing, Culinary